Kyle Rassweiler

Phone: +1-613-724-9141 Email: jobs@kylerassweiler.ca

Portfolio: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca Github: www.github.com/rassweiler

Summary

Engineering specialist with experience in both software and hardware development with schooling focused on embedded development and robtics.

Skills

Angular, Assembly(PIC), C++, CMake, Django, Git, HTML, JavaScript, Software

Mongoose, Node, PHP, Python, React, Redux, Typescript, VBA

Docker, Qemu/KVM, XCP-NG **Virtualisation**

Systems Arch, Debian, FreeBSD/OpenBSD, Proxmox, Windows

MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresgl, SQLite **Databases**

Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Zigbee Hardware

Projects

React Pagination

(Javascript, CSS, HTML, Node,

React)

Random Quote Machine

(Javascript, SCSS, HTML, Node, React, Bootstrap)

Markdown Preview

(Javascript, SCSS, HTML, Node, React, Bootstrap)

Krello

(Javascript, SCSS, HTML, Node, React, Redux)

A Hatchways assesment for React front-end work. The project required the addition of a pagination system for a sample blog site.

Source: https://github.com/kylerassweiler/165b69

A FreeCodeCamp project that generates random tweetable quotes using React.

Website: https://codepen.io/kylerassweiler/pen/rNdJzYO

A FreeCodeCamp project that will preview markdown input into a seperate editor window.

Website: https://codepen.io/kylerassweiler/pen/LYdQmMz

A simple Trello clone developed using react and redux with jest and enzyme for testing. Used Javascript, SCSS, and HTML to style the react components.

Website:

https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/posts/software/node/krello/

Demo: https://krello.kylerassweiler.com/ Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/krello

A Kawasaki robot backup parser library written in TypeScript. Kawasaki AS Parser

(Typescript, SCSS, HTML, Node,

Electron)

Website:

https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/posts/software/node/kawasaki-

Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/kawasaki-as-parser

Certificates

Free Code Camp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

July 2022 https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/kylerassweiler/

javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures

Free Code Camp Responsive Web Design

June 2022 https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/kylerassweiler/

responsive-web-design

Experience

Engineering Specialist PLC programming, Robotic Vision (Robeye system), 3D Factory

Design, Robot programming, Project Management, Tools Programming

(VBA, Powerbi, Electron).

Robotics Technician PLC programming, Robot programming, SCADA programing.

2014 - 2017

FIO Automotive

2017 - Present

TEMA (Toyota)

Operational Technician PLC programming, Robot programming.

2012 - 2014

Abbott Point Of Care

Education

Electro-Mechanical Engineering Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON.

Technician

2010 - 2012

Computer Animation Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON.

2007 - 2010